absolutely not absolutely
not next is a comment that I had under
one of the older tadalafil videos we did
few years ago but uh people are still
watching it and writing comments and uh
some comment wrote this um these guys
need to be honest and admit that they
recommend tadalafil to open up your
veins and arteries to move all that
thickens blood from trt is that true
girl
absolutely not absolutely not um less
than 30% of my patients are on toil um
in fact we don't really run into
erythrocytosis because we manage the
protocols and the frequencies correctly
and when we do run into mild
arthropyosis is generally a non-issue
unless you have severe comorbidities
that puts you at higher risks of pees
dvts Etc uh which again the coagul
coagulation Cascade especially intrinsic
coagulation really has nothing to do
with the rro sites this is a platelet
aggregation issue coupled with
arteriosclerosis or hardening of the
endothelial lining coupled with possible
calcification and plaque buildup from
triglycerides and poor unmanaged years
of
cholesterol and that is when arthrosis
starts to possibly be an issue when you
already have all the other Perfect Storm
um problems and now you're adding in a
mild viscosity increase to the blood
flow that is when we start to look at it
I'll be honest we generally don't start
men on trt who are
hypertensive and obese and have severe
issues that they need to address with
their primary care physician first so we
don't give men to dalil to mask a
potential problem that is not a problem
but you do recommend tadala fil for your
patients for we explain the mechanism of
how it works the benefits that it can
have and if they think that they are a
candidate for it by all means we don't
have a blanket procedure we don't have
protocols that say every man must or
should use a particular medication I'm a
fan of less is more the less medication
you can use to optimize your lifestyle
the better medications are not there to
just you know put an age on and say now
everyone should be on ABC if you need it
you benefit from it and it doesn't harm
you in any way then sure but like I said
I have about 70% of my trt patients are
not on tadalfil and there's nothing
wrong with that I you know I'd love
nothing more than have no patients on
any medications we don't sell
medications we're not a pharmacy so it
doesn't matter to me what medications
you use or don't I prefer you use less
medications you know we don't get paid
for giving you more drugs we simply get
paid for oversight management and
information and that information may
change but if it changes to reduce the
amount of medication you're on so be it
that's a win
[Music]